Ali Qureshi

uk.linkedin.com/in/alimqureshi 3 Grand Union House, Iver, The Ridgeway, SL0 9BU M: +44 7555 995 474 E: qureshi.ali94@googlemail.com

Personal Statement:

Over the past 6 years I've been working in the telecommunications sector, articulating marketing strategies and executing communications to deliver unique consumer experiences that drive real business impact. From launching new smartphones to management of influencers, digital media spend that maximises ROI or managing public relations; my experience spans across a variety of diverse roles and departments.

Employment:

Huawei/Honor (Mobile) Reading, 04/2018 - Present

Senior Marketing Manager

- Key focus around improving ROI expenditure across PPC/Display/Social media buy-in (improving conversions by upwards of 212%) and maximising ROAS through targeting/keyword optimisation.
- Creative asset development for social/OOH/media in-house and in co-ordination with freelance teams, ensuring brand consistency and efficient usage of resources to maximise delivery.
- Building a team of 25 in under 6 months for the Honor retail field force programme, including team recruitment/training, store mapping/grading and driving commercial alignment with channel partners.
- Management of the first Honor out-of-home activity, leading to a further 4 more taking place across key targeted cities within the UK (+£500K recurring budget). Supporting in driving x5 sell-out YOY.
- Project management of key launch and in-life marketing events, leading UK product launch events, including presenting to top industry media, organising multiple fan experiential activities and management of device pre-briefings (doubling PR coverage vs prior performance).
- Agency management across PR, advertorial, launch events, ATL/BTL advertising including public-speaking for the brand at key events, pre-briefs and launch events.

Samsung Electronics (Mobile) Surrey, 07/2016 – 04/2018

Omni-Channel Innovation Executive

- Launching new marketing creative/experience led campaigns driven by insights (developing 100% engagement uplift), including management of agency RFP to source new partners to build marketing initiatives resulting in over 20% cost reduction on executions.
- Partner sourcing and development on in-store/digital marketing initiatives (including projection technologies and website redesign), developing business sell-in, ROI analysis, project management and handover, resulting in certain work streams directly influencing ATL campaigns.
- Audit of existing marketing contracts with network partners and undertaking commercial renegotiations to maximise investment from a brand, marketing and fixture perspective; driving costs down by circa £500K and maintaining revenue projection.
- Management of a £50M budget between key stakeholders of the business, delivering upon objectives within timescales and creating a management 'blueprint' that is now being used as best practice.
- Trial and testing new initiatives in a structured phased approach (examples include analytics based security solutions), introducing 10% cost benefit and delivering strategic recommendations.

John Lewis Partnership/Samsung Electronics Slough, 10/2015 – 07/2016

Team Lead (Retail)

- Maintain an expert understanding of the Samsung mobile product portfolio along with an understanding of competitor offerings to showcase USPs and reach sales objectives.
- Responsible for training in-store JLP staff to drive product sales and awareness.
- Understanding the needs and requirements of B2B users to sell the most appropriate solution.
- Maintain brand visual and operational standards across the key retail Samsung fixtures.

Samsung Electronics (Domestic Appliance) Surrey, 01/2015 – 09/2015

Brand Marketing Executive

- Supporting the European Brand Director and Senior Brand Manager to create a marketing platform for the 17 European subsidiaries focused around the digital appliances product range (ATL/BTL).
- Responsible for developing the brand strategy, supporting subsidiaries to maximize their usage of marketing materials/assets with localizing opportunities.
- Managed the creative direction of 4 digital videos in collaboration with agency partners.
- Managing legal/financial status of projects, including the successful maintenance of a £2M budget, liaising with internal/external contacts to ensure the process runs efficiently.

- Sourcing new collaboration partners based around content, software, service and support in the education vertical.
- Attending key industry events, building relationships with potential B2B sales partners and supporting the sales team as part of the acquisition funnel.
- Improving communication between subsidiaries and European HQ through managing social channels and increasing user engagement on internal social network (+100% new registrations).

PC World/Samsung Electronics Slough, 10/2013 – 06/2014

Experience Consultant

Mothercare Slough, 09/2011 – 10/2013

Sales Advisor

Educational Background:

University of Reading, (BA Business & Management, 2012 - 2016)

2:1

Modules: Business Law, Business Statistics, General Introduction to Law, Introductory Financial Accounting, Marketing Management, 'Markets; Marketing and Strategy'.

Slough Grammar School (A2 Level)

(Mathematics, Business Studies, Applied I.T. & Media Studies)

Beechwood School (4 GCSE's A-C, 7 BTEC Distinction* - Merit)

(Mathematics - A, English Literature - A & English Language - A)

Work Experience:

Qureshi Consultancy Slough/Remote, 01/2020

Partner

- Started an influencer management agency with partner who is also a content creator, supporting in all aspects of brand building.
- Supporting in monetization strategy, brand outreach, content creation/creative direction.
- Developing relationships with agencies/brand marketing teams to generate new business.

DesignbyRecode Slough/Remote, 01/2017 – 02/2018

Founder

• Built a web development agency specializing in the SME sector - self-taught HTML/CSS based web design with entry level .PHP coding via CMS.

TheAccessoryGeek Slough, 06/2011 - 03/2013

Founder

- Built a mobile accessories based e-commerce business, specializing in the Amazon channel.
- Responsibilities included: inventory management, customer support, driving sales conversion and building key relationships with manufacturers to increase margins.
- Improving product distribution (logistics/delivery) within suitable timescales.

The Tribal Company (Student Enterprise), 10/2012 – 04/2013

Social Media Strategist/IT Manager

BoomBags (Young Enterprise - A Level Module), 01/2011 – 07/2011

Managing Director

Other skills / Interests

- Training (via professional skills training organization): impact and effectiveness, commercial awareness, effective agency relationship management, presenting with impact and stakeholder management skills training.
- Proficiency in Adobe Photoshop, Final Cut Pro, WordPress, HTML & CSS coding.
- IT Skills: ECDL (attainment: 2014).
- Languages: Fluency in English, Urdu, Hindi and Punjabi.